<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Wetlands</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The DEP Wetlands datalayer comprises two feature types, polygons and arcs (lines). The attribute codes in the polygon layer describe different types of wetland environments and the arc attributes describe line types based on adjacent polygon types or arcs defined as hydrologic connections. The wetlands are interpreted from 1:12,000 scale, stereo color-infrared photography (CIR) by staff at UMASS Amherst. The interpretation is field checked by Department of Environmental Protection (DEP) Wetlands Conservancy Program (WCP). Completed interpretations are then scanned and converted into rectified polygons and lines using standard photogrametric techniques by a consultant under contract to the WCP. Final quality control is performed by WCP GIS staff. The polygons and arcs are merged into a single layer (in coverage format) and additional attributes are added for the polygon features. The arc features are coded based on the adjacent polygon types, and attributes are added to the annotation subclass wet. An overlay process using the 1:25,000 Hydrography layer codes the PALIS_ID and PWSID attributes. The coding of the PALIS_ID and PWSID attributes was done using an overlay process and was not subject to the same quality control as the 1:25,000 Hydrography layer. Areas of wetlands in this layer may be shown as open water in the 1:25,000 Hydrography layer and so the coding of the PALIS_ID would not occur. Lines represented in the old 1:5,000 Streams layer are shown in this layer as hydrologic connections. These lines are only defined where they connect the various wetland types. These connections were not delineated within wetland areas, nor does they depict a complete stream network outside of wetland areas. Because the source scale of the CIR's is 1:12,000, plotting of open water features at a larger scale when overlaid onto existing 1:5,000 imagery will reveal areas of open water that are not delineated as such. It should be noted that the resulting wetlands shown in this datalayer are for planning purposes only. Wetlands boundary determination for other purposes, such as the Wetlands Protection Act MA Act M.G.L. c. 131 or local by-laws, must use the relevant procedures and criteria.</abstract>
      <purpose>Planning and analysis</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-71.270795</westbc>
        <eastbc>-71.158360</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.373789</northbc>
        <southbc>42.270458</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>wetlands swamps marshes marsh bogs water features ponds lakes hydrography hydrology hydrologic</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.4.1.5686</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>215</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>NAD 1983 StatePlane Massachusetts Mainland FIPS 2001</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>41.71666666666667</stdparll>
            <stdparll>42.68333333333333</stdparll>
            <longcm>-71.5</longcm>
            <latprjo>41.0</latprjo>
            <feast>200000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>750000.0</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000008155898179040834</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000008155898179040834</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Wetlands</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BoundarySource</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Source of boundaries</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>City of Newton</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>LiDAR</edomv>
            <edomvd>LiDAR generated elevations</edomvd>
            <edomvds>City of Newton</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Ortho</edomv>
            <edomvd>Aerial Photography</edomvd>
            <edomvds>City of Newton</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Combo</edomv>
            <edomvd>LiDAR and aerial photography</edomvd>
            <edomvds>City of Newton</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Site</edomv>
            <edomvd>Site visit-flagged</edomvd>
            <edomvds>City of Newton</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>State</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mass DEP Wetlands layer</edomvd>
            <edomvds>City of Newton</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of wetland</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>City of Newton</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of wetland</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>City of Newton</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SDE Feature Class</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt />
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180405</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>